<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Books on rs.io</title>
    <link>https://rs.io/categories/books/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Books on rs.io</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 May 2019 13:30:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://rs.io/categories/books/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>“The Ask” is an Entrepreneur’s Core Skill</title>
      <link>https://rs.io/entrepreneurs-core-skill.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2019 13:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rs.io/entrepreneurs-core-skill.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;div id=&#34;outline-container-org0fadbee&#34; class=&#34;outline-2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;org0fadbee&#34;&gt;
+ Other Notes on Entrepreneurial Expertise
    &lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;div id=&#34;text-org0fadbee&#34; class=&#34;outline-text-2&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I&amp;#8217;ve been going through the second edition of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/2GTREGS&#34;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Cambridge Handbook of Expertise&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt; after reading the first years ago, and was delighted to find the new edition has a chapter on excellence among entrepreneurs.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Review: A Random Walk Down Wall Street</title>
      <link>https://rs.io/a-random-walk-wall-street-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Aug 2014 01:31:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rs.io/a-random-walk-wall-street-review/</guid>
      <description>_(Note: this review originally appeared on a sister-site I&amp;#8217;m building out, Top Financial Advisor, but I&amp;#8217;m cross-posting it for readers here, as part of my ongoing book reviews. The last post in this series was the Advertising Secrets of the Written Word review and summary.)_
Ah, money. It doesn&amp;#8217;t taste good. It doesn&amp;#8217;t smell good. It can&amp;#8217;t keep you warm at night, and it won&amp;#8217;t love you back.
But you can trade it for something that does.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review and Summary: Advertising Secrets of the Written Word</title>
      <link>https://rs.io/advertising-secrets-of-the-written-word-review-summary/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2014 00:05:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rs.io/advertising-secrets-of-the-written-word-review-summary/</guid>
      <description>I made you a promise. I promised that book reviews were going to become a regular thing around here &amp;#8212; you know, in my Born to Run review and summary, where I said: &amp;#8220;I plan for this to be the first in a very long tradition of reviewing books, so stay tuned for more.&amp;#8221;
Well, now that I&amp;#8217;ve published reflections on one month vegan, it&amp;#8217;s time to stop procrastinating and make good on my word.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Born to Run: Book Review and Summary</title>
      <link>https://rs.io/born-to-run-book-review-summary/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2014 03:16:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rs.io/born-to-run-book-review-summary/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;m training for a half-marathon. As someone not terribly athletically gifted, it&amp;#8217;s been slow-going. Since I was going to spend the 4th of July weekend on the beach, electronically-secluded, I picked up a dead-tree copy of the book, Born to Run.
I&amp;#8217;ve seen a lot of people transformed into, well, the sort of runners that run with religious fervor after reading this book and I thought, hey, if it worked for them, maybe it&amp;#8217;d work for me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hard Books Are Overrated</title>
      <link>https://rs.io/hard-books-overrated/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2014 22:13:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rs.io/hard-books-overrated/</guid>
      <description>Hot air balloons take people on adventures. Books do, too.   Widely used calculus books must be mediocre.
— W. Rudin
 I&amp;#8217;ve noticed a phenomenon, especially in mathematics, where anyone asking for book recommendations invariably is recommended the least-gentle-but-still-reasonable textbook imaginable. A high school student might ask for an introduction to calculus and someone will tell them to read Principles of Mathematical Analysis. Looking for an introduction to programming?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Categories for the Working Philosopher</title>
      <link>https://rs.io/categories-working-philosopher/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2013 03:26:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rs.io/categories-working-philosopher/</guid>
      <description>Elaine Landry is working on putting together a book, Categories for the Working Philosopher. The list of topics that various contributors are working on is broad, including model theory, special relativity, quantum mechanics and ontology, biology, computer science, foundations, and more.
John Baez has posted an excellent abstract of his planned contribution. It talks about what happens when we attempt to formalize intuitive notions of equality. Some exciting relationships fall out, such as understanding equivalence as a path between two points in a topological space.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Summary: The Pursuit of Happiness</title>
      <link>https://rs.io/the-pursuit-of-happiness-summary/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2013 15:47:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rs.io/the-pursuit-of-happiness-summary/</guid>
      <description>This is a review and summary of David Myers&amp;#8217;s The Pursuit of Happiness.
General Thoughts on the Book in General, Generally The book is pretty good. I gave it a four out of five stars on Goodreads. If you&amp;#8217;re looking for an answer to the question, &amp;#8220;Who is happy?&amp;#8221; and are not interested in reading more rigorous texts, then this is a good place to start. If you&amp;#8217;re interested in the more pragmatic question, &amp;#8220;How can I become happier?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Summary: The Psychology of Happiness</title>
      <link>https://rs.io/the-psychology-of-happiness-summary/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2013 15:41:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rs.io/the-psychology-of-happiness-summary/</guid>
      <description>The Psychology of Happiness.&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;199&amp;rdquo; height=&amp;ldquo;300&amp;rdquo; srcset=&amp;ldquo;https://rs.io/wp-content/uploads/2013/08/psychology-happiness-michael-argyle-paperback-cover-art-199x300.jpg 199w, https://rs.io/wp-content/uploads/2013/08/psychology-happiness-michael-argyle-paperback-cover-art.jpg 200w&amp;rdquo; sizes=&amp;ldquo;(max-width: 199px) 100vw, 199px&amp;rdquo; /&amp;gt;This is my The Psychology of Happiness summary. The book is by Michael Argyle.
Notes on notes I didn&amp;#8217;t bother taking notes on parts of the book that contained information covered more thoroughly elsewhere or where the author&amp;#8217;s claims struck me as dubious. I also spent a while hunting down citations and then quit about half way through, figuring blogging ought to be fun.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Summary: Happiness: Lessons from a New Science</title>
      <link>https://rs.io/happiness-lessons-from-a-new-science-summary/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2013 15:34:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rs.io/happiness-lessons-from-a-new-science-summary/</guid>
      <description>Happiness: Lessons From a New Science.&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;195&amp;rdquo; height=&amp;ldquo;300&amp;rdquo; srcset=&amp;ldquo;https://rs.io/wp-content/uploads/2013/08/happiness-lessons-from-a-new-science-cover-195x300.jpg 195w, https://rs.io/wp-content/uploads/2013/08/happiness-lessons-from-a-new-science-cover.jpg 226w&amp;rdquo; sizes=&amp;ldquo;(max-width: 195px) 100vw, 195px&amp;rdquo; /&amp;gt;
This is my Happiness: Lessons from a New Science summary.
Happiness: Lessons from a New Science Summary What is the problem? Jeremy Bentham was a shy and kindly man, who never married and gave his money to good causes. He was also one of the first intellectuals to go jogging &amp;#8211; or trotting as he called it.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>