<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cognitive Science on rs.io</title>
    <link>https://rs.io/categories/cognitive-science/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cognitive Science on rs.io</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2014 12:30:04 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://rs.io/categories/cognitive-science/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A 60-Second Exercise That Boosts Goal Achievement By 20%</title>
      <link>https://rs.io/behavior-modification-techniques-if-then-rules/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2014 12:30:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rs.io/behavior-modification-techniques-if-then-rules/</guid>
      <description>The hero of our tale, Jason Padgett.  (Content note: this is an example of what I send out to email subscribers. You can sign up to receive more like it on any of the many forms scattered throughout the website, like the one at the bottom of this post.)
In 2002, Jason Padgett got into a fight. It was the fight of the decade, maybe the century. Not because Jason trounced his two assailants (he didn&amp;#8217;t), and not because it was a fair fight &amp;#8212; it wasn&amp;#8217;t &amp;#8212; but because of what happened the next morning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analogical Thinking: Concepts as Example Bundles</title>
      <link>https://rs.io/analogical-thinking-concepts-example-bundles/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2014 01:41:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rs.io/analogical-thinking-concepts-example-bundles/</guid>
      <description>Analogy is our best guide in all philosophical investigations; and all discoveries, which were not made by mere accident, have been made by the help of it.
—Joseph Priestley
 Words are not the stuff of thought.
This is straightforward to demonstrate. Present someone with a quote &amp;#8212; it can be anything, but for concreteness let&amp;#8217;s say you go with a bit of Thoreau: &amp;#8220;I was not designed to be forced.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I Like Surprises and You Should Too</title>
      <link>https://rs.io/why-i-like-surprises/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2014 02:25:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rs.io/why-i-like-surprises/</guid>
      <description>I love surprises.
Imagine a man &amp;#8212; oh, I&amp;#8217;ll just pick a name at random, let&amp;#8217;s call him James Randi. He&amp;#8217;s a staunch materialist. And not the &amp;#8220;I like to buy a lot of stuff&amp;#8221; kind of materialist, but the sort that believes everything is made out of atoms and quarks (and whatever quarks are made out of) and that magic is physically impossible.
Now, imagine that this man, fed up with arguing with hippies and magical thinkers generally, snaps and declares, &amp;#8220;I&amp;#8217;ll bet anyone a million dollars that they can&amp;#8217;t come into my laboratory and produce obviously supernatural phenomena.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Herbert Simon’s Ant</title>
      <link>https://rs.io/herbert-simons-ant/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2014 21:11:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rs.io/herbert-simons-ant/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;#8217;s a metaphor that comes to me by way of Nobel laureate and Turing award recipient Herbert Simon.
Imagine watching an ant on the beach. Its path looks complicated. It zigs and zags to avoid rocks and twigs. Very reminiscent of complex behavior &amp;#8212; what an intelligent ant!
Except an ant is just a simple machine. It wants to return to its nest, so it starts moving in a straight line.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creativity, Fan Fiction, and Compression</title>
      <link>https://rs.io/creativity-fan-fiction-compression/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2014 20:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rs.io/creativity-fan-fiction-compression/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;ve written before about the relationship between creativity and compressibility. To recap, a creative work is one that violates expectations, while a compressible statement is one that&amp;#8217;s expected.
For instance, consider two sentences:
 Where there&amp;#8217;s a will, there&amp;#8217;s a way. Where there&amp;#8217;s a will, there&amp;#8217;s a family fighting over it.  I suspect you find the second more creative.
Three more examples of creative sentences:
 When I was a kid, my parents moved a lot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Creative Process Demystified</title>
      <link>https://rs.io/creative-process-demystified/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2014 20:38:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rs.io/creative-process-demystified/</guid>
      <description>Jack Kerouac is a liar.
Okay, let me rewind. I don&amp;#8217;t know how much experience you&amp;#8217;ve had with creative writing types &amp;#8212; pale, imaginative creatures &amp;#8212; but let me tell you how they talk about Jack Kerouac. They say his name in sort of hushed, reverent tones, and whisper things like, &amp;#8220;Can you believe that he wrote On the Road in one sitting?&amp;#8221; Like great authors are some sort of gods.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creativity, Literature, and Compression</title>
      <link>https://rs.io/creativity-literature-compression/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2014 03:51:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rs.io/creativity-literature-compression/</guid>
      <description>But first, a joke:
 I was at a bar last weekend, chatting with this woman. She was decent looking. There was a lull in the conversation, so I say to her, &amp;#8220;Hey, I&amp;#8217;ve got this talent. I can tell when a woman was born after feeling her breasts.&amp;#8221; She doesn&amp;#8217;t believe me at first, but after a minute or so, she comes around. &amp;#8220;Go on, then,&amp;#8221; she says to me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Do We Think The Way We Do?</title>
      <link>https://rs.io/why-do-we-think-the-way-we-do/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2014 20:22:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rs.io/why-do-we-think-the-way-we-do/</guid>
      <description>I sometimes experience a sort of mental disconnect &amp;#8212; a sense of knowing what I&amp;#8217;m going to think before I bother to think it. Sort of like an experience of &amp;#8220;pure thought&amp;#8221; that is followed by a mental translation into words. It happens maybe a couple times a day and I wonder, &amp;#8220;Why do I bother thinking at all? At least in words. Why not stick to the stuff of pure thought?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>People All Think The Same</title>
      <link>https://rs.io/people-all-think-the-same/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2014 18:18:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rs.io/people-all-think-the-same/</guid>
      <description>On May 7th of 1997, Garry Kasparov &amp;#8212; the second strongest chess player of all time &amp;#8212; was hunched over a chess board. Both of his elbows rested on the table in front of him, with one hand clutching his forehead. His face sported a look of the purest determination.
His opponent felt nothing. It was Deep Blue, a machine built by IBM and, at the time, the most powerful computer chess player in existence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Savant Memory Says About The Limits of Memory</title>
      <link>https://rs.io/savant-memory-limits-of-memory/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2014 15:57:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rs.io/savant-memory-limits-of-memory/</guid>
      <description>Scientific American has published an article on savantism, which rattled a few ideas loose in my head. A savant is roughly defined as someone with cognitive deficiencies &amp;#8212; usually on the autism spectrum &amp;#8212; who displays superior performance in one area. A savant may be unable to speak or dress without assistance, but able to play the piano. Savantism comes in degrees &amp;#8212; one can be a savant by being an average piano player, given that they&amp;#8217;re functionally disabled in all other activities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effective Study Skills for College Students: “Why?” Questions</title>
      <link>https://rs.io/effective-study-skills-for-college-students-why-questions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2014 15:56:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rs.io/effective-study-skills-for-college-students-why-questions/</guid>
      <description>Consider two sentences:
 The llama was made out of watermelon flavored cactus. Policeman doe terminology star inconvenience recruit.  If I asked you to close this web page and then recall both sentences, you&amp;#8217;d have an easier time with the first sentence. It has meaning and structure &amp;#8212; even if a bit strange. I could make this still harder by adding a third sentence that&amp;#8217;s just a jumble of letters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Makes Something Interesting?</title>
      <link>https://rs.io/what-makes-something-interesting/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Feb 2014 03:45:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rs.io/what-makes-something-interesting/</guid>
      <description>Francis Galton, cousin of Charles Darwin and maybe best known for his work on intelligence, was a bit obsessed with the idea that people have certain innate traits. You know the movie Minority Report, where a special police department tries to predict crime before it happens? He sorta tried to invent it &amp;#8212; in 1883.
He had this idea, see, that you could predict whether or not someone was a criminal based on the structure of their face.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Science of Problem Solving</title>
      <link>https://rs.io/the-science-of-problem-solving/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2014 02:40:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rs.io/the-science-of-problem-solving/</guid>
      <description>Mathematics is like the One Ring in the Lord of the Rings. Once you&amp;#8217;ve loaded a problem into your head, you find yourself mesmerized, unable to turn away. It&amp;#8217;s an obsession, a drug. You dig deeper and deeper into the problem, the whole time unaware that the problem is digging back into you. Gauss was wrong. Mathematics isn&amp;#8217;t a queen. She&amp;#8217;s a python, wrapping and squeezing your mind until you find yourself thinking about the integer cuboid problem while dreaming, on waking, while brushing your teeth, even during sex.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Expert Memory: What Can Memory Experts Teach Us?</title>
      <link>https://rs.io/expert-memory/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2014 23:02:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rs.io/expert-memory/</guid>
      <description>That which we persist in doing becomes easier, not that the task itself has become easier, but that our ability to perform it has improved. —Ralph Waldo Emerson
 Malcolm Gladwell dragged the notion of deliberate practice into the public lexicon with the publication of his book Outliers. In short, world class performance depends not on talent, but on thousands of hours of a special sort of practice, deliberate practice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deciphering Core Human Values In A Society of Mind</title>
      <link>https://rs.io/core-human-values/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2013 04:00:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rs.io/core-human-values/</guid>
      <description>Know thyself? If I knew myself I would run away.
—Johann Wolfgang von Goethe
 Humans are evolutionary hacks. I&amp;#8217;m often not of one mind, or even two, but of four and sometimes more. Our brains seem to be locked in an eternal struggle, a constant clash of warring preferences. Consider the would-be comedian who, instead of working on his act, spends the day watching Family Guy reruns. He is of two minds: one wishes to watch Family Guy while another wants to brainstorm new routines.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>