<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Progress on rs.io</title>
    <link>https://rs.io/tags/progress/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Progress on rs.io</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 Aug 2019 20:22:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://rs.io/tags/progress/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>For progress there is no cure</title>
      <link>https://rs.io/for-progress-there-is-no-cure/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Aug 2019 20:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rs.io/for-progress-there-is-no-cure/</guid>
      <description>Finally and, I believe, most importantly, prohibition of technology (invention and development, which are hardly separable from underlying scientific inquiry), is contrary to the whole ethos of the industrial age. It is irreconcilable with a major mode of intellectuality as our age understands it. It is hard to imagine such a restraint successfully imposed in our civilization. Only if those disasters that we fear had already occurred, only if humanity were already completely disillusioned about technological civilization, could such a step be taken.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hazlitt’s Monster</title>
      <link>https://rs.io/hazlitts-monster/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2019 03:51:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rs.io/hazlitts-monster/</guid>
      <description>If it were indeed true that the introduction of labor-saving machinery is a cause of constantly mounting unemployment and misery, the logical conclusions to be drawn would be revolutionary, not only in the technical field but for our whole concept of civilization. Not only should we have to regard all further technical progress as a calamity; we should have to regard all past technical progress with equal horror.
–Henry Hazlitt, Economics in One Lesson</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spengler’s Man &amp; Technics (1931)</title>
      <link>https://rs.io/spenglers-man-technics-1931/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2019 04:54:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rs.io/spenglers-man-technics-1931/</guid>
      <description>In reality, however, it is out of the power either of heads or of hands to alter in any way the destiny of machine-technics, for this has developed out of inward spiritual necessities and is now correspondingly maturing towards its fulfilment and end. Today we stand on the summit, at the point when the fifth act is beginning. The last decisions are taking place, the tragedy is closing.
Every high Culture is a tragedy.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>