<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Economics on rs.io</title>
    <link>https://rs.io/categories/economics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Economics on rs.io</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2014 03:09:49 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://rs.io/categories/economics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Pareto Principle Examples and History</title>
      <link>https://rs.io/pareto-principle-examples-history/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2014 03:09:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rs.io/pareto-principle-examples-history/</guid>
      <description>Economics consists of theoretical laws which nobody has verified and of empirical laws which nobody can explain.
—Michal Kalecki
For a very long time, the Pareto law has lumbered the economic scene like an erratic block on the landscape; an empirical law which nobody can explain.
—Josef Steindl
 In the book that I&amp;#8217;ve been writing on keeping up in the information age (subscribe via email to receive a copy when it&amp;#8217;s finished), I&amp;#8217;ve touched on both Sturgeon&amp;#8217;s Law (&amp;#8220;90% of everything is crap&amp;#8221;) and the Pareto principle, as part of a section on filtering information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Worldbuilding, Worldbuilders, and Mathematics</title>
      <link>https://rs.io/worldbuilding-worldbuilders-mathematics/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2014 17:53:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rs.io/worldbuilding-worldbuilders-mathematics/</guid>
      <description>This week, I was introduced to the hobby of worldbuilding &amp;#8212; inventing imaginary places, making maps, elaborating histories. (The platonist in me prefers to think of worldbuilding as the discovery of fictional universes, rather than an act of invention.)
Tolkien There is a (perhaps apocryphal) tale that J. R. R. Tolkien got into a fight with his publisher over using the words &amp;#8220;elves&amp;#8221; and &amp;#8220;dwarves&amp;#8221; instead of &amp;#8220;elfs&amp;#8221; and &amp;#8220;dwarfs&amp;#8221;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Life Satisfaction of Economists</title>
      <link>https://rs.io/life-satisfaction-of-economists/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2013 18:44:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rs.io/life-satisfaction-of-economists/</guid>
      <description>Tyler Cowen has written a post on a paper about the life satisfaction of economists. It&amp;#8217;s a horrible paper. I don&amp;#8217;t like it at all.
Here are some reasons:
 The authors use satisfaction and happiness interchangeably. They are not the same construct and it will confuse those not familiar with the existing literature. The sample is taken from a few mailing lists of European economists. The study measures life satisfaction with a single question.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Terrible Future Isn’t: Drone Delivery Edition</title>
      <link>https://rs.io/drone-delivery/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2013 04:49:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rs.io/drone-delivery/</guid>
      <description>Last night, Amazon&amp;#8217;s CEO Jeff Bezos appeared on 60 Minutes and spoke about the possibility of using drones to deliver small packages (&amp;#8220;drone delivery&amp;#8220;). My gut reaction is the engineer&amp;#8217;s natural skepticism: I&amp;#8217;ll believe it when he&amp;#8217;s rolled out something that works instead of touting vaporware. (Remember hyperloop? Yeah, that&amp;#8217;s never going to happen.) That&amp;#8217;s not so fun to read about, though, so let&amp;#8217;s instead talk about the promise of drone delivery.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Criticism of Economics</title>
      <link>https://rs.io/criticism-of-economics/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2013 04:16:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rs.io/criticism-of-economics/</guid>
      <description>I don&amp;#8217;t have the requisite expertise to lay out compelling criticism of economics as a whole, and I suspect such an endeavor would be profitless (heh). The thrust of such an argument, though &amp;#8212; its quintessence &amp;#8212; is captured in this quote by Richard Feynman:
 See, I have the advantage of having found out how hard it is to get to really know something, how careful you have to be about checking the experiments, how easy it is to make mistakes and fool yourself.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>