<?xml version="1.0"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 
  <title>rs.io</title>
  <link href="http://rs.io"/>
  <link type="application/atom+xml" rel="self" href="http://rs.io/atom.xml"/>
  <updated>2012-07-18T01:34:17-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://rs.io</id>
  <author>
    <name>Robert Seaton</name>
    <email>possesed@gmail.com</email>
  </author>

  
  <entry>
    <id>http://rs.io/2012/07/18/weekend-moralist</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://rs.io/2012/07/18/weekend-moralist.html"/>
    <title>Weekend Moralist</title>
    <updated>2012-07-18T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Robert Seaton</name>
      <uri>http://rs.io</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s midnight. I&amp;#8217;m wide awake. I won&amp;#8217;t be sleeping tonight. I have the movie &lt;em&gt;Alien&lt;/em&gt; streaming on the television via the Boxee Box, but I haven&amp;#8217;t been paying any attention. I have only the vaguest notion of what&amp;#8217;s going on. I know they&amp;#8217;re on a spaceship and that they&amp;#8217;re being attacked by some parasitic life form. From the film&amp;#8217;s title and the creature&amp;#8217;s appearance, I gather (quite astutely) it&amp;#8217;s an alien.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m drinking coffee. The mug is off-white and curved, non-traditional. A sort of faux-retro look that could be described as &amp;#8220;modern.&amp;#8221; The irony does not fail to make an impression on me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve just swallowed two round red pills of acetamo-something for a headache, which the coffee is exacerbating. I keep drinking it, regardless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whenever some woman &amp;#8211; it&amp;#8217;s always a woman &amp;#8211; tells me that she&amp;#8217;s addicted to caffeine or Facebook or shopping or reality television or one of a million other banal, modern vices, I visualize the word imbecile tattooed across her forehead. Our society glorifies addiction, impulsiveness, instant gratification, the one-click checkout. Temperance: a cardinal virtue? Nah, a relic of the Victorian era.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our religions are no longer religion. Our religions are hobbies. Nietzsche had it wrong. God isn&amp;#8217;t dead. He&amp;#8217;s a dilettante, a dabbler, a weekend moralist.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://rs.io/2011/12/28/lets-try-talking</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://rs.io/2011/12/28/lets-try-talking.html"/>
    <title>Let's Try Talking</title>
    <updated>2011-12-28T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Robert Seaton</name>
      <uri>http://rs.io</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Lips move and sound happens, &lt;br /&gt; Words come together, sentences form, &lt;br /&gt; But communication never occurs, &lt;br /&gt; Nothing transfers. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One party to another: &lt;br /&gt; Talking, waving, motioning, &lt;br /&gt; Eyes wide, mouth agape, &lt;br /&gt; Ears closed. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Want connection? Meet rejection! &lt;br /&gt; No true things are ever spoken. &lt;br /&gt; Feel some feelings, don&amp;#8217;t try sharing, &lt;br /&gt; Talk about the things you&amp;#8217;re wearing. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A whisper, scream, or in between, &lt;br /&gt; If what you&amp;#8217;re saying: &lt;em&gt;it&amp;#8217;s important!&lt;/em&gt; &lt;br /&gt; Just remember, they&amp;#8217;re only playing &amp;#8211; &lt;br /&gt; an expected part, one they&amp;#8217;re portraying. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://rs.io/2011/11/01/launching-os-blog</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://rs.io/2011/11/01/launching-os-blog.html"/>
    <title>Launching OS Blog</title>
    <updated>2011-11-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Robert Seaton</name>
      <uri>http://rs.io</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve decided to take blogging seriously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last week, I purchased the beta of &lt;a href='http://technicalblogging.com/'&gt;&lt;em&gt;Technical Blogging&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and began formulating my attack plan. Originally, I had planned to use this domain, rs.io, as the foundation for an attempt at serious blogging, but I eventually discarded that idea, since io domains don&amp;#8217;t rank well in Google, &amp;#8220;rs&amp;#8221; isn&amp;#8217;t a keyword, and I didn&amp;#8217;t want to go through the hassle of rebranding this domain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first decision that &lt;em&gt;Technical Blogging&lt;/em&gt; recommends you make is deciding on a niche to target. I had a hell of a time figuring out what topic I could 1) write at least 30 articles about, 2) wasn&amp;#8217;t super competitive, and 3) I&amp;#8217;m an expert in. I spent a couple of hours agonizing over this, then it hit me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Operating systems! I&amp;#8217;m going to write about operating systems! See, I love operating systems. I love reading about &amp;#8216;em. I love thinking about &amp;#8216;em. I learned to program in C so that I could build my own operating system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With my niche decided, I sought out the perfect URL. I wanted osblog.com, but it&amp;#8217;s parked by GoDaddy. I tried to track down the guy that owns it, but he hasn&amp;#8217;t responded to my email, so I registered http://os-blog.com.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve written 3 articles so far, so it&amp;#8217;s time to officially announce &lt;a href='http://os-blog.com'&gt;OS Blog&lt;/a&gt; and add a link to it under Projects in the sidebar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m currently working on a series of posts that will serve as an introduction to the assembly programming that you&amp;#8217;ll need to know if you want to write your own operating system and, once I&amp;#8217;m finished, I&amp;#8217;m going to follow it up with a series of tutorials on building your own operating system. I&amp;#8217;m also working on a piece about the history of Unix. I have lots of other stuff planned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href='http://os-blog.com'&gt;Check it out.&lt;/a&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://rs.io/2011/10/22/the-un-debugable-machine</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://rs.io/2011/10/22/the-un-debugable-machine.html"/>
    <title>The Un-debuggable Machine</title>
    <updated>2011-10-22T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Robert Seaton</name>
      <uri>http://rs.io</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I get along well with most pieces of technology (not counting &lt;a href='http://rs.io/2011/10/19/i-hate-my-smartphone.html'&gt;my smartphone&lt;/a&gt;) and I make a capable troubleshooter, but there’s one piece of hardware where the slightest hiccup leaves me with a deep sense of foreboding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe you’ve guessed it: the printer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id='if_the_three_gorges_dam_is_a_marvel_of_modern_engineering_the_printer_has_to_be_one_of_its_blackest_marks'&gt;If the Three Gorges Dam is a marvel of modern engineering, the printer has to be one of its blackest marks.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m getting ready to junk another printer, part of a long line of now defunct devices. I’ve heard a number of stories from fellow nerds about faithful desktops, aged more than ten or fifteen years, that they’ve had to either junk or relegate to the basement since their machine’s hardware, still in working order, is just too dated. My own desktop has lasted more than 5 years and I still use it every day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have heard no such stories about printers, though, and I’ve never personally had one last more than two years. That alone leaves me feeling slightly uneasy about the devices, but what &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; frightens me about the printers I’ve owned, gentle reader, is that they are seemingly impervious to debugging attempts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you first buy a printer, you’ve got the pain of the initial setup to deal with. A task that can prove to be no small feat if you’re dealing with anything other than mainstream hardware. What, you want hook up your fancy wifi-enabled printer so that it’s shared over a network served up by a custom-built BSD router and you want the ability to print from Windows, OSX, and Linux machines? You’re in for a world of hurt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id='i_couldnt_figure_that_out_even_though_ive_made_it_through_a_number_of_gentoo_installs'&gt;I couldn’t figure that out even though I’ve made it through a number of Gentoo installs.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually, I gave up. I bought a standard router (well, kind of, it’s a Netgear WNR3500 running dd-wrt) and I was limited to printing from the Windows machines. By that point, though, the fight had been beaten out of me and I was happy to be able to print at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t have a disk drive and you’re planning on downloading the drivers? God help you, you’re well into the belly of the whale. I remember thinking: “Is this &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; the manufacturer’s site or just a clever attempt at serving up malware?” The site was that shady.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Things worked okay for about six months, and by “okay”, I mean that every once in a while the print queue would block on some phantom task but, thanks to a trick learned long past from Microsoft support, it’s just a quick trip to services.msc, kill the printer spooler, and you’re ready to go. Until it all breaks down again, then rinse and repeat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, once that six month mark rolled around, printing quality started to degrade. The printed pages were still readable, but random lines would be half-italicized. I tried re-installing the printer drivers, re-aligning the print heads, everything. I read the suggestions in every E-how article I could find.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nothing fixed it. Eventually, I just gave up, again. The machine still printed okay, readable, at least, just slightly garbled. The printer had defeated me, master debugger, twice, as all its brethren had defeated me years prior.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As of about a week ago, the machine has started to really go mad. Whole pages are lost or garbled, while others print fine. You might have to print a document five times to get one complete, legible copy of your work. Again, I haven’t got the first clue how to fix it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Suffice to say, I’ve had enough headaches debugging this machine. I’m just going to write it off as a lost cause, take it out to a field somewhere, and, well, &lt;a href='http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=l0_S_EdZ_I8'&gt;you know&lt;/a&gt;. Then I’ll buy a new one and start the entire process over again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sorry state of printer technology is baffling. I wonder: how do consumers manage to print anything at all? I can barely comprehend the suffering of the IT guy who is responsible for keeping an institution’s printers in working order. That surely must be the inner-most circle of Hell.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://rs.io/2011/10/19/i-hate-my-smartphone</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://rs.io/2011/10/19/i-hate-my-smartphone.html"/>
    <title>I Hate My Smartphone</title>
    <updated>2011-10-19T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Robert Seaton</name>
      <uri>http://rs.io</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I read &lt;a href='http://thisismynext.com/2011/10/18/exclusive-matias-duarte-ice-cream-sandwich-galaxy-nexus/'&gt;an interesting interview with Matias Duarte&lt;/a&gt;, Android&amp;#8217;s head of user experience, this morning. The article was pretty good, but that&amp;#8217;s not what I want to talk about. This is what I want to talk about:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;What we heard from everyone we talked to in the study was that they love these things (smartphones), they are a part of their lives. They&amp;#8217;re incredibly passionate about them. They can&amp;#8217;t live without them. That was awesome. But we also heard a lot of things we didn&amp;#8217;t like to hear.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This makes me sad because I feel like I&amp;#8217;m supposed to love my smartphone, and I don&amp;#8217;t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See, I&amp;#8217;m a geek &amp;#8211; or a nerd or a technologist or what-have-you &amp;#8211; and my life is fundamentally centered around interactions with computers, but here&amp;#8217;s the thing: I don&amp;#8217;t really a give a shit about my smartphone. My relationship with my smartphone is just plain &lt;em&gt;shallow&lt;/em&gt;, decidedly so when compared with how I feel about my desktop or MacBook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Actually, you know what, I hate my smartphone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before you start foaming at the mouth, gentle reader, my smartphone is running Android and not iOS, but &amp;#8211; before owning an Atrix &amp;#8211; I owned an iPhone 3G, and I hated that, too. This isn&amp;#8217;t about iOS vs Android. I hate them both.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, I&amp;#8217;m not saying that my smartphone isn&amp;#8217;t useful. It is. My computer, though, isn&amp;#8217;t just useful. It changes the way I interact with &lt;em&gt;everything&lt;/em&gt;. If I felt the same way about my computer as I do about my Android device, I would be thinking &amp;#8220;well, at least I don&amp;#8217;t have to use the phonebook to look this up.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id='i_love_computers_but_hate_my_smartphone'&gt;I love computers, but hate my smartphone.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s not that I don&amp;#8217;t know how to use my smartphone. It&amp;#8217;s true that I don&amp;#8217;t know the full potential of the device: all the touch gestures, useful applications, power user stuff, but, really, what is there to it? You can call people, browse the web, take photos, send text messages, and play Angry Birds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The block that I have is: I can&amp;#8217;t do anything &lt;em&gt;useful&lt;/em&gt; with a smartphone! I can&amp;#8217;t do work with it. Text input is just a huge pain and the screen is too small to do any useful reading. It&amp;#8217;s portable, sure, but I&amp;#8217;d always rather use a PC or laptop than a smartphone, if given the option.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I&amp;#8217;m sitting on the couch, I don&amp;#8217;t pull out my smartphone. I open up my MacBook. When I want to browse the web, I use my MacBook. If I&amp;#8217;m going to do some writing, like this post, &lt;em&gt;I don&amp;#8217;t use my smartphone&lt;/em&gt;, I use my MacBook. When coding or listening to music, I use my desktop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do use my smartphone to browse the web, on occasion, so there&amp;#8217;s that, but it&amp;#8217;s whenever I don&amp;#8217;t have my laptop or desktop handy. I only interact with one site at a time, and it&amp;#8217;s just not very pleasant. It feels very limited, not at all empowering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rest of the ways that I interact with my smartphone, they&amp;#8217;re all social and, as an introvert, it just doesn&amp;#8217;t hold a whole lot of appeal for me. My text messaging skill and finesse, especially when compared to my typing ability, it&amp;#8217;s pathetic. I hate trying to input text on the device, especially complex passwords: what a pain!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The least excusable failing of Android and iOS, I&amp;#8217;ve realized while writing this, is that I can&amp;#8217;t move from what I&amp;#8217;m working on with my MacBook or desktop and then to my smartphone. That would be great, even if the transition between form factors would maybe be a little awkward. Imagine if you could just resume your browsing session on your laptop or desktop from your phone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After all, the desktop and laptop markets, they&amp;#8217;re going to go the way of the workstation (and the dodo). They might remain in certain niches but, fundamentally, those markets are going to be disrupted by more portable options. The desktop market is already disappearing, cannibalized by laptops. That&amp;#8217;s why IBM got out of the PC market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#8217;re going to keep the laptop form factor for a while, I believe, but I think that they&amp;#8217;ll just be shells that you plug your smartphone into. The keyboard as input is still the best tool for the job, thus far, and there will always be a market for devices with screens larger than 4.2&amp;#8221;, so it doesn&amp;#8217;t make sense for that form factor to disappear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;#8217;s where Android and iOS should be headed: integration with the OS, empowering users, providing the means to create meaningful works on these devices. Computing isn&amp;#8217;t just consuming media and talking with your friends!&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://rs.io/2011/10/15/evolution-of-an-email-addict</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://rs.io/2011/10/15/evolution-of-an-email-addict.html"/>
    <title>Evolution of an Email Addict</title>
    <updated>2011-10-15T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Robert Seaton</name>
      <uri>http://rs.io</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;After quitting college and beginning the hunt for an entry-level programming position, I&amp;#8217;ve become addicted to email. This is my story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id='in_the_before_times'&gt;In the before times…&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There once was a time, not so very long ago, where I received two types of email. Type A: emails to confirm that I did, in fact, sign-up for some account with a valid email address, and type B: spam. My email account was useless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I began attending the sanctified institution that has been dubbed (with some sarcasm, I suspect) higher-learning, or college, they provided me with a new email account. This new account lacked such advanced, technically challenging to implement features such as IMAP or POP access. The only way to view your email, then, was through the UI provided by the college.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, luckily for us students, the college had gone to great lengths when it came to designing and implementing the user interface for our email accounts. The college administrators had first constructed a time-machine and, then, traveled to the year 1995 where they used their inflated 2010 dollars to buy the best 1995 designer that money could buy. They then had him design the UI for email access. Or maybe they just outsourced it, I&amp;#8217;m not sure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best part about this interface, besides the fact that it was the only way to access your email , was that you could only be logged into your account for 15 minutes at a time. If you were foolish enough to try to use the provided interface to compose any email of some length, then, when you hit the 15 minute threshold, you would be logged out and the email you were in the process of composing would be summarily destroyed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It may come as some surprise, but very few students used their provided email accounts. Some teachers would even go so far as to request your &amp;#8220;real email&amp;#8221; in order to contact you should class be cancelled. The teachers would then sell the real emails, along with any other personal information they had gleaned, to Chinese &amp;#8220;business men.&amp;#8221; The faculty was not paid well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On one occasion, a particularly overzealous teacher was collecting &amp;#8220;real email addresses&amp;#8221; so that she could contact students about doing public readings of their works at bookstores after the semester had ended. As I had no intention to continue pretending that I had any positive emotion whatsoever toward the teacher in question once the semester had ended (she had once marked me half-absent and I secretly hated her for this) and certainly no intention of staying in touch, I told her that my real email was, in fact, my school email. She did not believe me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ironically, I suspect the faculty&amp;#8217;s emails were accessed through Microsoft Live, such that they were not forced to share the punishment of using the school email interface with the student body.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id='we_approach_the_present'&gt;We approach the present.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This Fall, I made the decision to stop attending college, and instead focus on learning on my own and, also, seeking a job. I have no idea how most people get jobs. I suspect they leverage their social network, a friend makes an introduction, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Such a strategy is not viable in my case, seeing as I have a social network of about six people, none of whom are in a position to get me a job doing anything other than moving furniture. So, instead, I have been tracking down interesting companies with offices in the Chicago-land area and, then, emailing them my resume.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I now check my email compulsively. I&amp;#8217;ve installed a notification plugin in Chrome that informs me every time I get a new email and, when that occurs, I drop whatever I&amp;#8217;m doing and I check the email. It&amp;#8217;s like Christmas, except most of the time the email is just some stupid newsletter that was sent out to a billion people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, every once in a while, I get an email back from someone at a company. Unlike all the other emails I get, these are emails written by actual, real-life human beings, and let me tell you: when you&amp;#8217;re as starved for human contact as I am, those emails start looking pretty damn good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyways, sometimes the email lets me know that the company is not looking to hire anyone, or that they don&amp;#8217;t do internships, or whatever. Those emails are okay. I don&amp;#8217;t mind getting them when they are written by human beings. Sometimes, though, I get a positive response, like &amp;#8220;why don&amp;#8217;t you stop by our office for some coffee&amp;#8221; and those emails, gentle reader, are magic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those emails provide the trifecta for the creation of habit forming behavior and stimulate all kinds of reward centers in the brain. They contain precious human contact, they offer the potential for more human contact, and they present the possibility that the company may hire me, which enables me to dream about getting out of the house everyday and going to an office (lots of human contact!) where I get to write software. What could be better?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can&amp;#8217;t imagine getting &lt;em&gt;too many emails&lt;/em&gt;. It seems to me that people who are getting too many emails are very lucky indeed, since their inbox is full of opportunities, and when have you ever heard someone complain about having too many opportunities?&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <id>http://rs.io/2011/10/14/why-you-should-start-blogging-again</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="http://rs.io/2011/10/14/why-you-should-start-blogging-again.html"/>
    <title>Why You Should Start Blogging (Again)</title>
    <updated>2011-10-14T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Robert Seaton</name>
      <uri>http://rs.io</uri>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The benefits of blogging are many.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id='blogging_facilitates_powerful_introspection'&gt;Blogging facilitates powerful introspection.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my years of blogging, I have found that writing in general, and blogging specifically, are great ways to discover truths about yourself. When you sit down and distill your thoughts into the written word, you are forced to cut out all of the junk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, I don&amp;#8217;t know about everybody, but I naturally tend towards introspection and analysis, so when I start distilling my thoughts into a blog post, I get curious. I start asking myself: &amp;#8220;Why is it that you think that? Is this thought part of a pattern? Does your personality influence this thought or does this thought influence your personality?&amp;#8221; Then, I start to analyze the analysis, and so on. It&amp;#8217;s turtles all the way down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I&amp;#8217;m getting at is: when you blog, you&amp;#8217;re presented with a great opportunity to learn about yourself, and knowing about yourself is a very good thing because you will a) become aware of your strengths and weaknesses and with this awareness you will become resilient to attempts by people to exploit your weakness and you will gain the ability to exploit your strengths, and b) you will be able to make future decisions faster and with more confidence since you will be aware of why you have come to such a conclusion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id='blogging_crystallizes_thoughts_and_thought_processes'&gt;Blogging crystallizes thoughts and thought processes.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you set about writing a blog article, your ideas and feelings about the topic in question may not be clearly defined. By the time you have finished your blog post, your thoughts and thought processes will have become clearly defined, crystallized. This is a necessary byproduct of writing about your ideas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you set about communicating an idea, in our case through writing, you must do so with a certain level of clarity &amp;#8211; otherwise, no one will be able to understand your ideas. Personally, I always try to present an idea as clearly as possible by making my writing, first and foremost, unambiguous and, also, as simple as possible. This maximizes communicability: the effectiveness of getting your idea across.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since you are forced to present your ideas with clarity, you must refine them. You have to sit and think &amp;#8220;how would I express this idea in words?&amp;#8221; Through this refinement, your ideas become concrete, crystallized and you gain something important: understanding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id='blogging_improves_your_ability_to_express_yourself'&gt;Blogging improves your ability to express yourself.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blogging is a form of communication and the benefits of being able to effectively communicate should be self-evident. Think about it. What is society based on, if not communication? Imagine living without the ability to effectively express your ideas and emotions. Want to tell that special someone how you feel? I hope you&amp;#8217;re able to communicate effectively or it will come out all wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Communication and expression are literally fundamental to every aspect of being human. There are few, if any, skills more valuable than effective communication. Think of all the great men throughout history and consider where they would be without the ability to effectively communicate. Would we even know Einstein&amp;#8217;s name if he hadn&amp;#8217;t been able to communicate so effectively, to explain &lt;a href='http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mass%E2%80%93energy_equivalence'&gt;mass-energy equivalence&lt;/a&gt; in such a way that even a layman can grasp the power of the idea?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you blog, you are honing your ability to express yourself. You&amp;#8217;re &lt;em&gt;practicing&lt;/em&gt;. How effectively you manage to communicate in your blog, that&amp;#8217;s not super important, unless you plan on becoming mega-popular, but when you&amp;#8217;re interviewing for that job you really want, I&amp;#8217;ll bet you&amp;#8217;ll be glad that you&amp;#8217;ve been practicing expressing yourself effectively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id='people_will_enjoy_your_creation'&gt;People will enjoy your creation.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It took me a long time to realize this, but people enjoy reading blogs, even blogs about nothing. That&amp;#8217;s why blogs are so popular. When you write a blog post, you&amp;#8217;re creating something of value, something that people enjoy. That&amp;#8217;s really powerful! It&amp;#8217;s a good thing to think about now and again. It will help keep you motivated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whatever you write, I&amp;#8217;m sure people will find it entertaining or informative. When I was 12, I kept a blog just about my daily life and people loved it. They just ate it up. A 12 year-old kid blogging about his day, and they loved it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just think about it: you have the power to create something that other people will enjoy.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  
 
</feed>
