<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Relationships and Sex on rs.io</title>
    <link>https://rs.io/categories/relationships-and-sex/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Relationships and Sex on rs.io</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 23:27:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://rs.io/categories/relationships-and-sex/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Prolonged Eye Contact and Attraction: What The Science Tells Us</title>
      <link>https://rs.io/prolonged-eye-contact-attraction-science-tells-us/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 23:27:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rs.io/prolonged-eye-contact-attraction-science-tells-us/</guid>
      <description>&amp;nbsp;
&amp;nbsp;

Belladonna means &amp;#8220;beautiful woman&amp;#8221; in Italian, but it&amp;#8217;s also the name of a type of plant. The origins of the term belladonna are uncertain, but date back to at least 1554.
It&amp;#8217;s been suggested (and this is my favorite theory) that the name might be related to belladonna&amp;#8217;s use as a cosmetic. Women would consume the plant in order to dilate their pupils, in an attempt to enhance beauty.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who initiates divorce the most? Men or women?</title>
      <link>https://rs.io/who-initiates-divorce-the-most-plus-breakups/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2014 22:11:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rs.io/who-initiates-divorce-the-most-plus-breakups/</guid>
      <description>Pop quiz. Who initiates divorces and break-ups? Men or women?
The answer is women. Women are more likely than men to initiate a break-up.
 First, men are less likely than women to initiate break-ups (Hegelson, 1994; Hill, Rubin, and Peplau, 1976), and noninitiators of a break-up are more likely than initiators to experience distress (Sprecher, Felmlee, Metts, Fehr, &amp;amp; Vanni, 1998).
—Handbook of Gender Research in Psychology, Volume 2 (pg.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Secretary Problem Explained: Dating Mathematically</title>
      <link>https://rs.io/the-secretary-problem-explained-dating/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2014 18:17:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rs.io/the-secretary-problem-explained-dating/</guid>
      <description>I was, to put it mildly, something of a mess after my last relationship imploded. I wrote poems and love letters and responded to all of her text messages with two messages and all sorts of other things that make me cringe now and oh god what was I thinking.
I learned a few things, though, like when you tell strangers that your long-term relationship has just been bulldozed as thoroughly as the Romans salted Carthage, they do this sorta Vulcan mind-meld and become super empathy machines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Love Is Not A Choice And Other Tools For Thinking</title>
      <link>https://rs.io/love-is-not-a-choice/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2014 03:45:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rs.io/love-is-not-a-choice/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;m not much of a romantic. If I wanted to hack romance I&amp;#8217;d start with going through all the literature on the mate preferences of chimpanzees, bonobos, and great apes generally. Only after I&amp;#8217;d taken in the unfiltered humans-are-big-monkeys view would I turn to something with a more human emphasis. It&amp;#8217;d be a few months before I started, you know, dating.
When I do listen to other people speak about passionate love &amp;#8212; mostly internet people &amp;#8212; it&amp;#8217;s surreal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Where are the women in the IT industry?</title>
      <link>https://rs.io/women-in-the-it-industry-sexism/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2014 22:46:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rs.io/women-in-the-it-industry-sexism/</guid>
      <description>It has become fashionable as of late for media outlets like Gawker and others to attack Silicon Valley, math, computer science, and the hard sciences generally for being unfriendly to women. This does not strike me as much different than the bullying of math and computer nerds during high school, except now we&amp;#8217;ve exchanged jocks for journalists, and it&amp;#8217;s covered in a not-very-convincing veneer of social justice-y but-we&amp;#8217;re-bullying-nerds-because-oppression.
The most convincing challenge to this narrative was written by Scott Alexander in a comment, which was a response to many other specific concerns not likely to appeal to most readers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Polya Urn Model Dissolves The Gender War</title>
      <link>https://rs.io/polya-urn-model-dissolves-gender-war/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2014 01:54:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rs.io/polya-urn-model-dissolves-gender-war/</guid>
      <description>Now listen, you queer, you stop calling me a crypto-Nazi or I’ll sock you in the goddamn face and you’ll stay plastered.
—William Buckley1
 I&amp;#8217;m not sure whether the two sexes are about to stage World War III over gender issues or if I&amp;#8217;m in some sort of gender bubble but, for whatever reason, I&amp;#8217;ve been hearing about gender issues daily for the past six or so weeks and, as part of a gender, I have some thoughts on it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bad at math? Have you tried steroids?</title>
      <link>https://rs.io/testosterone-and-math/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2013 02:39:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rs.io/testosterone-and-math/</guid>
      <description>Men with lower T performed better than other groups on measures of spatial/mathematical ability, tasks at which men normally excel. Women with high T scored higher than low-T women on these same measures.1
Our findings are the first that present the relationship between testosterone and the broad range of general IQ in childhood. The boys of average intelligence had significantly higher testosterone levels than both mentally challenged and intellectually gifted boys, with the latter two groups showing no significant difference between each other.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is veganism for women?</title>
      <link>https://rs.io/vegan-women/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2013 00:05:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rs.io/vegan-women/</guid>
      <description>I recently tried my hand at making this bean-based, vegan taco filling (recommended), and noticed something curious while reading the recipe&amp;#8217;s comments:
 I made this for my vegetarian daughter and it was so good I served it to the whole family for dinner.
This stuff is the bomb. Even my carnivore husband loved it!
My daughter is vegan, while the rest of the family isn&amp;#8217;t. My husband usually can&amp;#8217;t stand non meat recipes, and loved this one!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are introverts ever happier than extroverts?</title>
      <link>https://rs.io/introverts-happier-than-extroverts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2013 23:48:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rs.io/introverts-happier-than-extroverts/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;#8217;s one actual perk of being a wallflower:
 Although extraverts are generally happier than introverts, Kette (1991) found that extraverted prisoners were less happy than introverted prisoners.
 — Well-Being: Foundations of Hedonic Psychology</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Women Friends are Better Friends</title>
      <link>https://rs.io/women-friends/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2013 17:00:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rs.io/women-friends/</guid>
      <description>The Justice Department now seems to be saying that prison rape accounted for the majority of all rapes committed in the US in 2008, likely making the United States the first country in the history of the world to count more rapes for men than for women.
Christopher Glazek
Women receive prison sentences on average only about half as long as men, and about half of that advantage is due solely to gender bias.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>