<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Human Values on rs.io</title>
    <link>https://rs.io/categories/human-values/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Human Values on rs.io</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2014 12:30:04 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://rs.io/categories/human-values/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A 60-Second Exercise That Boosts Goal Achievement By 20%</title>
      <link>https://rs.io/behavior-modification-techniques-if-then-rules/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2014 12:30:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rs.io/behavior-modification-techniques-if-then-rules/</guid>
      <description>The hero of our tale, Jason Padgett.  (Content note: this is an example of what I send out to email subscribers. You can sign up to receive more like it on any of the many forms scattered throughout the website, like the one at the bottom of this post.)
In 2002, Jason Padgett got into a fight. It was the fight of the decade, maybe the century. Not because Jason trounced his two assailants (he didn&amp;#8217;t), and not because it was a fair fight &amp;#8212; it wasn&amp;#8217;t &amp;#8212; but because of what happened the next morning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spinach, unhealthy? Reflections on one month vegan</title>
      <link>https://rs.io/spinach-unhealthy-reflections-one-month-vegan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2014 03:47:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rs.io/spinach-unhealthy-reflections-one-month-vegan/</guid>
      <description>Rewind. It&amp;#8217;s August of last year. I&amp;#8217;ve just published a post on the reasoning behind certain &amp;#8220;strange&amp;#8221; beliefs. It covers veganism, cryonics, existential risk, simulationism, polyamory, and singularitarianism.
Then, in September, I write about the curious gender imbalance among vegans &amp;#8212; that there are 3 woman-vegans for every man-vegan.
If we take those as indicative of the feelings of past-me, I&amp;#8217;ve been open to the idea of veganism for about 10 months now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prolonged Eye Contact and Attraction: What The Science Tells Us</title>
      <link>https://rs.io/prolonged-eye-contact-attraction-science-tells-us/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 23:27:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rs.io/prolonged-eye-contact-attraction-science-tells-us/</guid>
      <description>&amp;nbsp;
&amp;nbsp;

Belladonna means &amp;#8220;beautiful woman&amp;#8221; in Italian, but it&amp;#8217;s also the name of a type of plant. The origins of the term belladonna are uncertain, but date back to at least 1554.
It&amp;#8217;s been suggested (and this is my favorite theory) that the name might be related to belladonna&amp;#8217;s use as a cosmetic. Women would consume the plant in order to dilate their pupils, in an attempt to enhance beauty.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Unreasonable Effectiveness of Checklists</title>
      <link>https://rs.io/unreasonable-effectiveness-of-checklists/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 May 2014 22:33:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rs.io/unreasonable-effectiveness-of-checklists/</guid>
      <description>Dr. Peter Provonost had a problem. People were dying and &amp;#8212; to borrow a line from Fight Club &amp;#8212; not in the Sylvia Plath, Tibetan Buddhist, we&amp;#8217;re-all-dying-so-get-used-to-it sense of the word.
No, this is hospital kind of death we&amp;#8217;re talking. I mean death in all of its macabre horror. You know, the horror we cover up with euphemisms like &amp;#8220;passing away&amp;#8221; and pretend that white sheets and a sterile environment somehow make the notion of oblivion no longer panic-inducing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Creative Process Demystified</title>
      <link>https://rs.io/creative-process-demystified/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2014 20:38:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rs.io/creative-process-demystified/</guid>
      <description>Jack Kerouac is a liar.
Okay, let me rewind. I don&amp;#8217;t know how much experience you&amp;#8217;ve had with creative writing types &amp;#8212; pale, imaginative creatures &amp;#8212; but let me tell you how they talk about Jack Kerouac. They say his name in sort of hushed, reverent tones, and whisper things like, &amp;#8220;Can you believe that he wrote On the Road in one sitting?&amp;#8221; Like great authors are some sort of gods.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What affects your personal identity? You’re a sponge.</title>
      <link>https://rs.io/what-affects-your-personal-identity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2014 21:54:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rs.io/what-affects-your-personal-identity/</guid>
      <description>That thing is the most badass of all sea slugs, the nudibranch. The nudibranch is more a family of sea slugs than one species, and the name comes from the Latin nudus, meaning naked, as it has no shell.
This slug is not remarkable for its nudity, although &amp;#8220;naked sea slugs&amp;#8221; would make a good name for a band. No, the remarkable thing about the nudibranch is that it eats jellyfish, digests their stinging cells, and then incorporates those same cells into its body as a defense mechanism.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Secretary Problem Explained: Dating Mathematically</title>
      <link>https://rs.io/the-secretary-problem-explained-dating/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2014 18:17:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rs.io/the-secretary-problem-explained-dating/</guid>
      <description>I was, to put it mildly, something of a mess after my last relationship imploded. I wrote poems and love letters and responded to all of her text messages with two messages and all sorts of other things that make me cringe now and oh god what was I thinking.
I learned a few things, though, like when you tell strangers that your long-term relationship has just been bulldozed as thoroughly as the Romans salted Carthage, they do this sorta Vulcan mind-meld and become super empathy machines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effective Study Skills for College Students: “Why?” Questions</title>
      <link>https://rs.io/effective-study-skills-for-college-students-why-questions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2014 15:56:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rs.io/effective-study-skills-for-college-students-why-questions/</guid>
      <description>Consider two sentences:
 The llama was made out of watermelon flavored cactus. Policeman doe terminology star inconvenience recruit.  If I asked you to close this web page and then recall both sentences, you&amp;#8217;d have an easier time with the first sentence. It has meaning and structure &amp;#8212; even if a bit strange. I could make this still harder by adding a third sentence that&amp;#8217;s just a jumble of letters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Love Is Not A Choice And Other Tools For Thinking</title>
      <link>https://rs.io/love-is-not-a-choice/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2014 03:45:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rs.io/love-is-not-a-choice/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;m not much of a romantic. If I wanted to hack romance I&amp;#8217;d start with going through all the literature on the mate preferences of chimpanzees, bonobos, and great apes generally. Only after I&amp;#8217;d taken in the unfiltered humans-are-big-monkeys view would I turn to something with a more human emphasis. It&amp;#8217;d be a few months before I started, you know, dating.
When I do listen to other people speak about passionate love &amp;#8212; mostly internet people &amp;#8212; it&amp;#8217;s surreal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Science of Habit</title>
      <link>https://rs.io/the-science-of-habit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2014 22:21:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rs.io/the-science-of-habit/</guid>
      <description>The truth is that everyone is bored, and devotes himself to cultivating habits.
—Albert Camus, The Plague
 To my perpetual dismay, I&amp;#8217;m not a rational agent with limitless willpower. I&amp;#8217;m not every moment brimming with novel insight and original computation. No. I&amp;#8217;m a habit machine, a behavior-executor, on autopilot &amp;#8212; a creature of habit. (Or &amp;#8220;habbit,&amp;#8221; for illiterate googlers.) I do the things that I do because that&amp;#8217;s how I&amp;#8217;ve done them in the past.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Expert Memory: What Can Memory Experts Teach Us?</title>
      <link>https://rs.io/expert-memory/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2014 23:02:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rs.io/expert-memory/</guid>
      <description>That which we persist in doing becomes easier, not that the task itself has become easier, but that our ability to perform it has improved. —Ralph Waldo Emerson
 Malcolm Gladwell dragged the notion of deliberate practice into the public lexicon with the publication of his book Outliers. In short, world class performance depends not on talent, but on thousands of hours of a special sort of practice, deliberate practice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Future Generations Are Your Legacy, All Of Them</title>
      <link>https://rs.io/future-generations-legacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2014 03:15:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rs.io/future-generations-legacy/</guid>
      <description>I have heard tell of a time in a man&amp;#8217;s life where he begins to worry less about his own dreams and invests more in living through his children. His children will be his legacy.
This is a very real and common thing that people value: leaving behind something of some permanence, and children are one means to achieving this. I would like to suggest, though, a broader view of things, of thinking about humanity as a whole as a legacy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When Is It OK To Break The Rules?</title>
      <link>https://rs.io/when-is-it-ok-to-break-the-rules/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2014 03:11:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rs.io/when-is-it-ok-to-break-the-rules/</guid>
      <description>I propose a new way of thinking about rules. Not as something that distinguishes between what one is allowed and not allowed to do, but rather as a penalty that certain actions carry. Not moral law sent down from on high, but costs for implementing certain strategies.
Imagine the virtual city of Neebar, ruled by a horde of half-ox, half-man with a penchant for all things camel. Neebar is notable because it has a strange penal code: running water is illegal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts On The Police Body Cameras Privacy Debate</title>
      <link>https://rs.io/police-body-cameras-privacy-debate/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2014 02:54:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rs.io/police-body-cameras-privacy-debate/</guid>
      <description>There&amp;#8217;s a link on Reddit to the sort of story that the internet can&amp;#8217;t get enough of: police abuse. This time, the NYPD sodomizing a black man with a plunger.
People love to hear about the abuse of power. Something along the lines of it keying into our gossip reward centers with a side of moralizing. To indulge in creating my own evo-psych just-so story: gossiping about the misdeeds of your hated rival, head-chimp Heephop, might be a way of polling public sentiment as to your chances at a successful coup.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Is Wisdom?</title>
      <link>https://rs.io/what-is-wisdom/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2013 04:30:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rs.io/what-is-wisdom/</guid>
      <description>There&amp;#8217;s an art to knowing when;
Never try to guess.
Toast until it smokes &amp;amp; then
20 seconds less.
—Piet Hein, &amp;#8220;Timing Toast&amp;#8221;
 When one first learns a theory, one tends to take it a bit too seriously. I&amp;#8217;ve heard that people who later convert to Christianity tend to be much more fervent believers than those who are raised with it, for example, or note the brain damage that first exposure to libertarianism and Ayn Rand seems to do to young people, the same with economics, or the phenomenon where people who have just taken a psychology course tend to see disorder everywhere.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deciphering Core Human Values In A Society of Mind</title>
      <link>https://rs.io/core-human-values/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2013 04:00:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rs.io/core-human-values/</guid>
      <description>Know thyself? If I knew myself I would run away.
—Johann Wolfgang von Goethe
 Humans are evolutionary hacks. I&amp;#8217;m often not of one mind, or even two, but of four and sometimes more. Our brains seem to be locked in an eternal struggle, a constant clash of warring preferences. Consider the would-be comedian who, instead of working on his act, spends the day watching Family Guy reruns. He is of two minds: one wishes to watch Family Guy while another wants to brainstorm new routines.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>